telesign.com 2013-05-12

# Privacy Policy | TeleSign

This policy was last updated on August 1, 2012

TeleSign has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our strong commitment to privacy. TeleSign is deeply committed to respecting and protecting your right to privacy and takes your privacy seriously. We have very strict privacy policies and we strive to keep your personal information secure. This policy covers the collection and use of information obtained through the websites on which this policy appears as well as the information we collect and process at the direction of our clients via application programming interface (API) endpoints.

###  Privacy Policy Overview

TeleSign products, websites, and corporate doctrine are committed to respecting your privacy and the protection of the personal information shared with us.

By helping you understand our Privacy Policy, we open the way to better communications and service. We handle your personal information with care and respect.

TeleSign has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s [Web Privacy](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/program_requirements_website_privacy) and [TRUSTed Cloud](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/TRUSTed-cloud/) program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions.

The TRUSTe program covers information that is collected through our websites (located at [www.telesign.com](http://www.telesign.com/)) and services. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@telesign.com](mailto:privacy@telesign.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

###  Safe Harbor

TeleSign complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. TeleSign has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view TeleSign’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

###  Information Collected

TeleSign collects and uses personal information to provide outstanding customer service, easy access to our software products and services, and to increase the availability of our deliverables.

We may collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Billing information such as credit card number, and billing address
  * Unique identifiers such as user name, account number, password
  * Preferences information such as product wish lists, order history, marketing preferences

We collect information in a variety of ways. When you:

  * Correspond with us
  * Call to make a purchase
  * Make an online purchase
  * Request service
  * Register products online
  * Register to attend training
  * Participate in a survey and evaluations
  * Apply for Internet services
  * Join an email mailing list
  * Request support for TeleSign products
  * Request information
  * Participate in promotions
  * Submit questions or comments
  * Provide information by phone or form
  * Submit personal details through our websites
  * Through the use of our services

We also collect supplemental information from other sources:

  * From third parties such as TeleSign alliances and partners
  * Via credit reporting agencies
  * From publicly available sources of information
  * At conventions, trade events, and expos

###  Collection Notice and Use of Your Personal Information

When your personal information is collected directly from you, we give you notice of our intended use through a “purpose statement”. The purposes include:

  * Providing you with information, goods, or services
  * Promoting and marketing TeleSign and for research purposes
  * Providing statistical information to government and other organizations
  * Assessing, receiving, managing, or terminating receipt of goods or services assessing, managing, and terminating joint ventures and collaborative projects as required by law (responding to a subpoena, warrant, audit, or agency action, or fraud prevention)

Your personal information is also used to provide you with information regarding your account and the products or services you purchase from TeleSign. Collecting your personal information enables us to better understand your needs and interests, improves our service, and personalizes communications.

When third party sources are used, we will attempt to contact you regarding the reason your personal information is being collected.

We will retain the information collected through our websites and the data we process on behalf of our client for as long as needed to provide services described in this privacy policy.

###  Cookies and Other Technologies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies both session ID cookies and persistent. A session cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our sites. We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once.  Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our sites.  You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. If you reject cookies, you may still use our sites, but your ability to use some areas of our sites, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

_Analytics / Log Files_  
Our websites and services gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.  This information is used to administer and improve performance, diagnose server problems, and to help ensure the security of our websites and services.

_3rd Party Tracking_  
The use of cookies and web beacons by our partners and service providers is not covered by our privacy statement.  We do not have access or control over these technologies.  Our partners and service providers use cookies and clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help us better manage content on our sites and services provided. The information gathered by clear gifs is not tied to our site visitors’ or customers’ personally identifiable information.

_Social Media_  
Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as a “Share” button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

###  Disclosing Personal Information

We may share the information collected on our websites with other companies who may contact you to market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [privacy@telesign.com](mailto:privacy@telesign.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy). We do not share the information collected through our services with third parties for their promotional purposes.

At times, personal information may be transferred to outside organizations, including TeleSign-related companies, partners, or other third parties who provide us with assistance/various outsourced business functions, such as submitting email and SMS communications or processing payments. These third parties are authorized to use the provided information only as necessary to provide their services. TeleSign takes reasonable steps to ensure that third parties protect your personal information. Additionally, your personal information may be disclosed to:

  * Your representatives or legal advisors
  * Credit-reporting
  * Fraud-checking agencies
  * TeleSign advisors, accountants, auditors, and lawyers
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * If TeleSign is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets,  you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our websites of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information

###  Access to Information

To ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete, and up-to-date, we take reasonable steps whenever we collect or use it.

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, ask to have it removed from a public forum, or testimonial on our sites by making the change on our client portal page or by contacting us via one of the methods listed in the contact section below.  We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

If access to your personal information is denied, or TeleSign refuses to provide you with access, we will provide you with the appropriate non-access or refusal information.

We have no direct relationship to the data being processed within the TeleSign services. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to TeleSign’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests us to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 business days.

###  Safeguards and Security of Information

The security of your personal information and our Clients’ information is important to us.  When you enter sensitive information (such as login credentials) we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

TeleSign takes reasonable steps to protect the personal information that we hold. We safeguard the security of your data with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.  Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Your personal information may be stored either in hardcopy documents, as electronic data, or in TeleSign software or systems to help protect it from misuse, loss, unauthorized access, modification, or disclosure.

TeleSign will take every reasonable step to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information that is no longer needed.

The TeleSign sites use advanced encryption on all web pages requiring personal information. This protects the confidentiality of your personal and credit card information when transmitted online.

###  Communications

TeleSign may send you information about your account, about the products and services you purchased, or to remind you about upcoming events that you have signed up for. TeleSign does not send commercial electronic messages unless the relevant electronic account holder consents or TeleSign is otherwise permitted to send them. To unsubscribe from our alerts or announcements, simply access the unsubscribe option within the TeleSign email communications or unsubscribe via this email address: [unsubscribe@telesign.com](mailto:unsubscribe@telesign.com?subject=Unsubscribe%20&body=Please%20unsubscribe%20me%20from%20your%20list.%20).

###  Additional Information

_Links to 3rd Party Sites_  
Our sites include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from ours. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

_Blog_  
Our websites offers publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blogs, contact us via one of the methods listed below.  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

_Testimonials_  
With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name.  If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us via one of the methods listed below. 

_Surveys_  
We may provide you the opportunity to participate in surveys on our sites.  If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.  The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and email address), and demographic information (such as zip code). We use this information to better understand the users of our sites.

_Changes to This Policy_  
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our sites prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

###  Contacting TeleSign Regarding Privacy Issues

If you have any questions about these practices, or wish to issue a concern or complaint, please contact us:

Address: TeleSign Corp. 4136 Del Rey Ave. Marina del Rey, CA 90292

Email: privacy@telesign.com

Telephone: +1 310 740 9700

We will respond to your question or complaint as soon as possible, and will try to resolve any issues as soon as possible.
